之前  我们看到可以向display方法传递一个整形参数
Earlier, we saw that we could pass a number into the display method.
接下来我们进一步聊聊方法的输入和输出的不同
Let's talk more about the different inputs and output of a method.
我们来看一下MainActivity里的submitOrder方法
Let's look at the submitOrder method in the MainActivity as an example.
比如在这个方法中你有一堆代码
Say you have a bunch of lines of code in that method.
当用户点击Order按钮的时候
When the user clicks on the Order button,
按钮会触发这个submitOrder方法
it will trigger this submitOrder method to be called.
Android设备会将这些指令从头到尾运行一遍
The Android device will execute each of these instructions from top to bottom,
当它调用calculatePrice方法时  它会
and when it hits the calculatePrice method call it will
跳到calculatePrice方法被定义的地方
jump over to where the calculatePrice method is defined.
比如这个方法被定义在MainActivity文件的结尾
Say that this is defined at the bottom of the MainActivity file.
Android设备会从头到尾运行每一句指令
The Android device will execute each of these instructions from top to bottom of
然后它会自动跳回submitOrder方法
the method, and then it will jump back to the submitOrder method.
然后  它会继续运行指令直到
Then, it will continue executing these instructions until it hits the end
方法的结尾
of the method.
当calculatePrice方法被调用的时候
When the calculatePrice method is called,
我们可以传递一堆输入参数
we can pass a bunch of inputs over so
这样当我们运行这些代码的时候  我们可以使用这些输入数据
that when we're executing these lines of code, we can use these input values.
这个方法调用的最终结果是
As a result of this method,
我们可以返回一个输出值
we can pass a single output value back to the caller.
这样输出值可以用于接下来的代码中
That way, the output value can be used in the subsequent lines of code.
在Java中  我们将输入叫做方法输入参数
In Java, we call the inputs to a method input parameters, and
我们可以没有或者有多个输入参数
we can have zero or more input parameters.
在Java中  我们将输出叫做返回值
In Java, we call the output a return value,
我们可以有零个或者一个返回值
and we can have zero or one return value.
举个例子  calculatePrice方法可以接受一个
An example of an input parameter is passing the quantity
输入参数
over to the calculatePrice method.
这个方法可以利用这个值计算整个订单的
That way, this method can use the quantity to figure out the total price
最终价格
of the whole order.
然后我们可以将最终的价格作为返回值返回
Then, we can pass that total price back as a return value.
然后在下面这个submitOrder方法
And then in the submitOrder method, down here,
我们可以用这个最终价格来做其他的事  比如在屏幕上显示
we can use this total price to do other things, like display it onscreen, or
或者创建订单等等
create receipt, or anything like that.
总结一下  这里是我们定义calculatePrice方法的地方
So to summarize, this is where we define the calculatePrice method, and
这里是我们调用它的地方
this is where we call it.
我们想要创建一个方法能够计算咖啡的价格
We want to create a method to calculate the price of a coffee order.
目前  我们在submitOrder方法里直接计算价格
Currently, we calculate the price directly in the submitOrder method, but
但是计算价格的逻辑未来会有一点复杂
the logic to calculate the price is going to get a little more complicated.
所以我们需要单独的方法来做这件事
So let's move it into its own method.
有了单独的方法  我们就不需要到处重复拷贝和粘贴
Then we can call it as many times as we want without copying and
代码了
pasting the code everywhere.
随着大家Android开发经验的增加  你就能更加准确的判断
As you gain more experience in Android development, you'll gain better judgment
什么时候需要创建新的方法或者什么时候不需要
on when to create a new method for something or when you don't need to.
不过这需要更多的经验和时间的积累
This will just come with more experience and more time.
那么我们来创建我们在MainActivity里的
So, this is the first time we're going to be creating
第一个新的方法吧
a new method in the MainActivity on our own.
为了避免我们写的不规范  大家先来
Instead of starting by writing it from scratch, we want to start by learning to
看一些代码片段来学习一下什么是正确的方法
recognize what is a correct method by reading some code snippets.
在指导大纲里  我们给了大家三个选项
So in the instructor notes, we're going to provide you three options.
阅读一下这三段代码  看看哪一段正确
Read over these three code snippets and determine which
实现了计算订单的价格
option correctly implements the method to calculate the price of the order.
当你点击指导大纲的链接的时候
When you click on the link in the instructor notes,
你就能看到对应A、B、C选项的代码片段
you'll see this just has code for options A, B, and C.
这里这样做的目的就是
The goal here is for
为了帮助没看过代码的大家快速适应代码阅读
you to become comfortable with reading code that you've never seen before.
我们之前还没有详细介绍过创建可用方法的规则
We haven't gone over the exact rules for what makes a valid method, but
但是我希望大家能够尽量猜一下你认为最正确的选项
I want you to make your best guess on which option you think is most correct.
我也鼓励大家用Google搜索一下
I also encourage you to Google search for
看看如何定义一个Java方法
more information on how to define Java methods.
随着你不断阅读搜索到的结果
As you click through the different search results,
开发文档里你不懂的部分也会慢慢的明白
you'll come across information in the documentation that you don't understand.
如果大家不能完全理解页面上的所有内容也请不要着急
But I want you to become comfortable with not understanding everything on
因为这很正常  一般人都无法完全理解所有的内容
those pages, because it's perfectly normal to not understand everything.
大家需要做的就是快速浏览一下文章  找到你理解的和
All you need to do is just skim the articles for what you understand and
你觉得和问题相关的部分即可
what you think is relevant to the problem at hand.
那么开始读代码吧
So, go ahead and read the code for
上网搜一搜相关的内容
these three options, look up some information online, and then make your
然后尽量猜猜如何正确定义calculatePrice方法
best guest on how to correctly define the calculatePrice method.